Hereby call the meeting to order at 07:01PM.
The first item on the agenda is
roll call and seating of alternates.
Unfortunately,
I see only one member of the Commission,
Jed Larson,
present.
And we don't have any alternates to seat,
so I'm afraid we do not at present have a quorum for the meeting.
I was previously informed that Mr. Hallisey, Commissioner Hallisey, would be unable to attend the meeting.
And I don't see
Commissioner Smith
on the call.
That said, failing a quorum, I regret we cannot conduct any business or proceed with the agenda.
>> George, it looks like Allison's iPad is trying to sign in. I think that's
one of the alternates.
>> Well,
actually not yet because there hasn't been an appointment
or swearing in by
Board of an appointment by the the Board of Selectmen
or
a swearing in to make it official.
I was informed
this
would have been on the agenda
that
Gabriel Anderson,
who we had recommended
and whom the
Board of Selectmen had
recommended for appointment,
has declined that appointment.
And Mr. Monroe,
who we recommended
for appointment I believe that Mr. Monroe is using Allison's iPad
based on last time meeting.
Ms. Monroe has not yet been appointed
by the Board of Selectmen.
So
as I say, unfortunately, we'd prefer
an alternate to be seated,
and we therefore do not have a quorum
for the meeting.
And we can't conduct any business.
I'm holding on for just a moment in the hopes that Mr. Smith will join the call.
I don't have his contact information at hand, so I can't
communicate with him directly to see if he might be
available
to join the call.
Does anyone have contact information
for Ed Smith
other than email,
which I'm afraid would not be effective in this situation?
>> George, I got his phone number if you want to try and give him a call.
>> Okay,
let me
jot that down.
It would be 860,
I assume.
942942.
7416.
>> 7416.
Okay, I will mute myself.
Mr. Smith says that he will join the meeting
shortly.
Okay, I see
Commissioner Smith is now on the call.
We now have a forum,
and I will call the meeting to order at 07:11PM.
Third item on the agenda,
additions or changes in order to the agenda. Are there any suggestions
for additions or changes
to the agenda?
Okay,
seeing no indication, we'll proceed
then to,
item number four, public comment. If any members of the public
wish to speak on the items on the agenda,
you can contact me or Mindy, the board clerk by chat, and we'll unmute you.
Or
if you're on video
you could raise your hand
to,
thus literally raise your hand,
to indicate a desire to speak
to any item on the agenda.
Okay, well seeing no indication,
I'll proceed then to item number five of the agenda, approval of minutes.
I will entertain first a motion to approve the minutes for September 15
regular meeting.
>> I'll make a motion to approve the minutes from September 15 regular meeting.
>> Thank you. I'll Judd Larson moved.
I'll second the motion. Okay. So Judd Larson
moved,
Ed Smith,
seconded,
to approve the meetings. Any discussion,
on those minutes?
Amendments, corrections,
whatever.
Give you all a minute to make sure you've reviewed them
Commissioner Larson, are you ready to proceed with a vote?
I'm all set.
>> Commissioner Smith, ready to vote?
I'm all set. Okay, I'll call for a vote on the motion.
Commissioner Larson?
Aye.
Commissioner Smith? Aye.
And aye, Vice Chairman Elliott, also vote aye. The motion carries three-zero-zero.
Next,
we have minutes from the special meeting and site walk
conducted
at one hundred twenty nine Hebron Road
on September 19. Again,
there are only two of us who are actually there, I will move to approve those minutes
and ask for a second.
I'll second. Okay.
>> As an item of discussion, I would propose I use the term
seasonal
water course
at a couple of occasions in the minutes.
And I would like to revise
that. I think I may have used the term water course inadvisedly
and incorrectly
and I would like to change
terminology
for whatever it appears
to
the
terminology
let me make sure I get this straight
seasonal or
storm event
runoff.
Since there was no clear channel
in
the wetland area that we observed,
I don't know that we're entitled to call it a seasonal water course.
So I would move to
revise
the
minutes
accordingly.
Any comment on that?
None for me. Okay,
Commissioner Larson.
I'm all set.
>> Okay,
then
I will
move to
amend the minutes accordingly
and I'll take a second.
I'll second.
>> Okay and now we vote to amend
the minutes.
Commissioner Larson.
Aye.
Commissioner Smith.
>> And Vice
Chairman Elliott also vote aye. So it's three-zero-zero.
And now the, again, any other comments
or revisions,
corrections
to the minutes of that sidewalk special meeting?
Mr. Larson,
do you have any?
No other comments. Okay,
>> in that case,
I'll
move to a vote on the amended minutes.
Commissioner Larson?
Aye. Commissioner Smith? Aye.
And Vice Chairman Elliott also votes aye, so the motion is three-zero-zero.
Okay, we can move on now to item number six of the agenda permit applications.
The first one is IWWC
from Gary Partridge,
Lakeside Drive. Application to connect
to construct
or erect a 20 by 20 foot outbuilding storage shed
in the Andover Lake Upland review area. We received that application
last
meeting,
and
I believe that
well, yeah, those meetings minutes reflect.
We asked if there was any
plan
to
mitigate
the
impact
of that construction
on the
watershed and runoff.
We have subsequently
received
a communication,
a couple of items
added to that application.
I think the first
was a note to the effect
that the gravel pad
for
the shed
and the
specialized
or gutter and downspout system
that would introduce
the
runoff into the gravel pad
would be
a mitigating
element
in the plan.
Are there any other
comments or considerations
Commissioner Larson?
No, I'm all set.
>> Okay,
Commissioner Smith, did you have any comments on that application?
No comments.
>> Okay,
Mr.
Wagner,
were you
trying to unmute you. Okay. You go. Okay.
You're unmuted.
So
were you in communication
with the applicants
about this
mitigation?
>> Yeah. We we met over there when we discussed all the different options.
Gary wanted to avoid excavation.
And then when I went there, I mean, it looked like you wouldn't wanna excavate because there's several large rocks in that area. So, like, that would just cause
more
erosion and who knows how rock how big those rocks are anyway.
So yeah, we talked about a few different options, and then I I think the one he came up with is pretty good.
>> Okay, so in your opinion that
would be a sufficient
mitigation and
avoid the runoff
issue.
>> Three quarter
inch gravel provide plenty of room for the for drainage and then the way it'll be designed with the gutters run
basically uphill
dump
in front of the shed and then run back down through underneath the shed
and all percolate into the ground.
>> So any runoff from the
roof will end up basically end up in the gravel.
>> Yeah, gets directed to the uphill side of the gravel and then percolates into the soil
from there.
>> Okay, good.
Okay, so if there are no further comments,
I will proceed to
ask for
sorry, my phone was ringing.
Ask for a motion to approve the
application
with standard conditions
for, I guess, a two year period
would be more than sufficient in this case
and with the mitigation as specified in the amendments to the plan.
>> I'll make a motion to approve the application of 151 Lakeside Drive subject to the standard conditions
of approval.
I second the motion.
Okay, I'll call for a vote.
Commissioner Larson.
Aye.
Commissioner Smith.
>> And I Vice Chairman Elliott vote aye, so the motion carries three-zero-zero.
Will issue, remember there is a two week delay and we will issue
a
standard notification
of that approval.
You very much. You're welcome.
Thank you.
>> Moving on,
referring to the agenda. Okay, the second is
IWWC
twenty
twenty seven,
Ruby And Negen Puerto 129
Hebron Road
the
three part application
for wall and fence in ground pool and utility shed
and
a two car garage with accessory apartment.
Before we
proceed with comments from members present,
I should note that I received a communication
from
Commissioner
Halsey
already referred to in the minutes.
He pointed out that
the
sidewalk construction that we noted on the sidewalk
was not
included on the submitted plan,
that the submitted plan did not include
any reference
to the
or the submitted application,
I should say
did not include septic
system
alterations
that would be associated
with the
garage and apartment construction.
And he also
asked if
additional clearing
might
be required
for any of the activities
in the permit request.
So
I want that reflected in the record
of the meeting since Mr. Hallisey was unable to attend.
I'll ask now if Commissioner
Larson or Smith
have comments or questions
on the
the application
and then we'll proceed to some of the additional materials that have been received
since our last meeting.
Commissioner Larson.
>> I
did have
three comments. One,
when we were out doing the sidewalk,
it appeared that there was a rather large
pile of split wood
in the wetlands
up on in the area behind
and to the right of where the swimming pool would go.
Okay.
>> I guess the
second comment is
that
the application requires
alternatives that were considered
but not
chosen
with respect to mitigating
the impact on the wetlands.
And I didn't see anything in the application
that addressed
that.
And my third comment is that with the fence
being proposed
to go through the wetlands,
I just had a question if we should consider this an activity
of significant
impact
to the wetlands.
And those were my comments.
>> Right. And with regard especially to comment number three, yes, we will address that question
subsequently.
Commissioner
Smith, did you have any questions or comments on the application?
No, I defer to Mr. Larson's comments.
>> Okay.
Agent Wagner, have you met
with the
applicants
since
our last,
since our site walk?
>> No,
I had
some email
back and forth.
I think a phone call. That was it.
>> Okay.
Then that brings me to the additional materials.
We received.
And here, I've got to refer to my notes.
We did receive,
first of all, of course, a letter
from engineer Brandon Hanfield.
And
we
received a sketch
of the
proposed
fence
indicating
how
cutouts
might be used to
avoid impairing flow
from
seasonal
or
stormwater
runoff.
I had,
again, the same comment about alternatives
considered.
Some of those are spelled out in Mr. Hanfield's
letter.
I also question
the
object and the necessity
of the fence. We don't really understand,
we don't have any indication in the permit application
what the
the purpose is
purely aesthetic
or is there some functional
consideration
involved there.
We don't know how much of an area is being drained
by the again seasonal
some water runoff
in the well. We
don't have any topography
and it was hard to judge on the sidewalk because the terrain is quite rough.
So
there seems to be a good deal of information
that we are going to require before we can consider
this application.
And
I think prominent among them is the question of whether or not this is a significant
impact.
The letter from Brandon Hadfield
stated unequivocally
that he felt that the construction activity in the wetland
would constitute
a significant
activity.
Now as the Commissioner is aware and the agent is aware, the applicants may not be aware,
this would automatically
trigger
a public hearing
on the application
if we determine that it's a significant
activity.
And
I would
ask the commissioners
for their input
on that question.
First, Commissioner Morrison,
We could of course do this in the form of motion, but I'd rather discuss it informally first.
So Commissioner Larsen.
What
exactly was your question, George? How
>> do you feel about
Mr. Hanfield's comment that he considered this a significant
impact?
>> I agree with it. I think putting a fence across wetlands
is something that does have the potential. And I know the drawing indicates that
it won't restrict the flow, it still
has a significant,
it has the potential to have a significant impact on the wetlands.
Okay,
Commissioner Smith.
>> I have the plans, I have not visited the site, so I defer to Mr. Larson.
>> Okay,
I'm somewhat reluctant to take an official action given the fact that we only have
three or five
members
of the Commission
present.
On the other hand, if we don't take action on, if we don't make a resolution
on this,
the
application is still going to be in abeyance and we can't move forward
with addressing
any of the other concerns.
I'm going to
ask our board clerk if she can bring up that letter
engineer Hanfield
for screen sharing I can't share the screen that I'm looking at but
I want to make sure that everybody has that
available
and in front of them.
Would it be this one?
>> Yes exactly.
Okay, a couple of points I want to make here. First of all,
the referenced documents
in the first three bullets
do not include
the
amended drawing
for the fence with cutouts.
But other than that, it appears to reflect the same information we're working with.
And
then
following that,
the review comments
from engineer Hanfield,
the septic he addresses the septic system, which again
Commissioner Hallisey had brought up.
We don't have
information
regarding
the
soil
survey,
particularly we don't have the soil scientists and the map
that delineated
the inland wetlands. They are delineated on the plan,
but again we don't know who is responsible for that delineation.
We
don't have a convenient summary of any sort of the impact
and
the area,
not just the
area in which the fence would be constructed, but the area of disturbance,
which would be,
as engineer Hanford points out, considerably greater than the area occupied defense per se,
since there would
highly likely be
machinery
impacts
and
possibly grading
and other alterations
of topography
to erect
the fence as shown on the plan.
Furthermore,
within the Upland Review area,
Hanfield has proposed
or
I should say suggested
some alterations
which,
along
Commissioner Larson's
comments,
could be made
activities in the Upland Review area.
And again, we have not seen those addressed.
And I don't understand the force main and
trench and pipe but I assume that it refers to septic
system
upgrades that would be required
to accommodate
the
construction.
And again, as I pointed out earlier,
the
concrete and stone wall
would be
likely to be a
significant impact
and that we don't have the information you need regarding
the actual impact
of that activity.
So it appears to me at this point that the application
is
deficient
in several regards
and that we certainly cannot approve it
at this point.
And
secondly,
that as it's likely
to
involve a significant
impact,
we should probably
make that ruling
and
proceed
to the next steps.
>> Yeah, I can comment now looking at this letter, I had not seen that and it does appear to me that this could be a blueprint for the applicant to use to try to get more information
at the next meeting for the Wetlands Commission.
Commissioner Larson?
>> As I look at the first comment for consideration by the Commission.
I would think that the new septic system would be part of the application because that's instrumental
to
the building of the garage with the apartment above And so
I think
our review
does have to include the
septic system.
I agree.
>> Okay, so we're agreed that the
deficiencies
so
far enumerated
should be addressed in the application
and that
Mr. The engineer Hanfield's
comments
can serve as a
and the comments that we've made on
the record in this meeting
can serve as a guide
to the applicants
in
addressing
those deficiencies.
I would say then
I
think that we should
make a ruling
on the
issue of whether it's a significant impact
in order so that we can in fact move this process forward
in an orderly fashion.
>> I can clarify
something about the septic system.
This is agent Wagner.
It was
the system that's on the plan is, it was approved previously when they did an addition to the house.
They they
just added to the plan when they resubmitted it.
So
that septic system,
hasn't been constructed yet to my knowledge, but it
has been approved.
>> So agent Wagner, I'm sorry, agent Wagner, does that make moot then our concerns about the new septic system as it applies to this application?
>> Well, if it would need to be, my understanding is that it would need to be built to
for the garage to be the garage apartment
that's proposed to be connected to it. Like, you would need to upgrade the septic, but it's already been approved
through a previous application.
>> And the upgrade would be sufficient to accommodate
not only the
expansion of the existing structure,
but also
the additional load,
which would constitute essentially one bedroom
and I guess a couple of bathrooms
if I recall the plan.
So would the septic system
approved
be sufficient to accommodate
those additions?
>> I was so I talked to the sanitarian that approved it and
I yeah, I think she's she said it was
it was sufficient,
but it would need
public health,
Connecticut Public Health approval
because it's a separate building that's getting connected to it and that hasn't happened yet.
>> Okay, well then we
presume then that that will be addressed
in the course of the application,
you know, or within the within the time frame of the applications being considered.
We have, as I understand it, until
February
under the new guidance,
and I don't know what the impact of a public hearing will be on our timeline
off the top of my head, but in any event we certainly have adequate time to receive further information
about the septic and its appropriateness
for the
proposed activity.
Thanks for that clarification,
Agent Wagner.
Okay, so the
question that we have to resolve, as I say, is
will the
construction of the fence in the wetlands,
not to mention the Upland Review Area,
constitute a significant
activity,
under the regulations.
And I would entertain a motion to that effect so that we can
resolve it.
>> I'll make a motion that the activity described in the application on 129
Hebron Road
be considered a significant
activity impact
for purposes of the application.
And I second the motion.
>> Okay, is there any further discussion?
Seeing
no indication,
any other comment from the commission?
Okay,
I'll ask for a vote on the motion. Commissioner Larson?
Aye.
Commissioner Smith?
>> And aye, Vice Chairman Elliott also vote aye. So the motion
to declare the activity significant
impact
carries
three-zero-zero.
We
will
I'm afraid,
have to defer
a
scheduling of hearing
since we only have three of the five commissioners available.
But I understand that this will entail a public hearing
and that we will have to work out how this is done in the age of Zoom.
I hope that
others may have had the experience
to carry us through
that
requirement.
>> Excuse me, I have one question because
I think when you started the conversation
at the meeting you mentioned something about
the front, I think that doesn't have nothing to do with the wetland,
right?
That's one in the
comments
he has for
the wood you know, I know that's going to be removed at some point because when we was cleaning the yard when we don't know nothing about wetland and nothing like this because everything is new for us,
so we just put it there but that's because that's going to be removed at some point. And
for the activity what we're gonna do there, because we're not gonna use any machine to
to drill the the land in the wetland area,
it's gonna be by hand, so it's not gonna be nothing
seriously
consideration
to make any damage to the wetland area. Okay, well, you'll have your opportunity
>> to make these points
in public hearing,
since, you know, against we have ruled
that it will be a significant activity.
Now,
that's not to say that your comments
aren't,
well, again, you'll have the opportunity to make those comments
and
we'll certainly be taken into consideration
in our final
decision
with regard to
approving or denying the permit application.
Can I ask a question, sir? Well,
>> I'll entertain one more question, but we do have to move on with the rest of our agenda.
Go ahead. So
>> since I see that the issue here is defense, right? That's the most concerning issue for you guys? That's
>> the one that we've identified as being a
significant impact in the wetlands. There's no activity proposed to construct in the wetlands per se.
>> Okay.
So if we submit a separate application for the fence and just submit another application
or leave one application for the fence, whichever one, and submit a new application, even if we have to pay the fee again, that's fine,
for the shed, the pool, and the rest of the stuff. Do
you think it will be better? That way we don't have to wait too long to do the other
garage and the shed
in the apartment?
I'm sorry.
Let's just go for the hearing for That was a good question.
>> And
I'm not sure what the process would be.
It seems to me there would have to be an amended application.
It had occurred to me that having
all those
three elements
did make the application
excessively complex
and
hence more difficult.
>> Burj, I have a comment.
Jud, go ahead. And one of the things that
could also concern me, I'm
not
all that knowledgeable about it yet,
but was when the
letter from
engineer Hanfelt
discussed the backwash
or the backflush
from the swimming pool
and that backflush being in close proximity to the wetlands.
Wasn't sure
how that impacted
and I thought that could have a significant
impact as well.
>> Point well taken.
But again, to answer the question about amending the application
essentially to separate out
the fence and
I suppose that with
more information
and
again, Mr. Hanfield
did
propose
an alteration
of the pool configuration
and shed location.
And that might mitigate
the issue of
the
pool
impact
on the wetlands per set.
But
off the top of my head, unfortunately, I'm not familiar with what would have to be done
to
revise
or to you know to alter the application.
Agent Wagner do you have any
comment on that?
>> I think because it
should be able to just submit a new site plan without
like a revised site plan that doesn't include the fence
because it hasn't, the permit hasn't been denied yet or anything. You don't have to modify So
it could just be like a revised site plan
removing the fence,
a wall,
and then
you could
put that on a later application as its own thing.
>> Right, and with, again, with the
mitigation of the pool impact,
Yeah, that seems to me probably the most straightforward way
to do that, essentially an amended application
with a plan that does not include
the fence
and
again
addressing
the potential
impacts from the other
activities.
But that would certainly simplify matters in terms of considering the
considering the
application.
I think we can
hold off
on further action
until
you've had the opportunity
to
amend the application.
I think our ruling now is that the application as
it stands
includes a significant impact,
but
a revised application
an amended application
might not be.
>> All right so I believe that we will just amend the application and do two separate things.
Or do you want to do, since you guys are saying that you guys are concerned for the pool as well, do the fence and the pool
or just do the fence? What is your advice so we don't have to be waiting for the next meeting and then finding out that we have to revise something else? Well,
>> think that you have to determine your priorities
in terms of you know what you want to include
in
the permit application
in the amended permit
application
to be able to move forward
and have us consider the application
at
our next meeting.
>> Okay,
if I have any questions about what paperwork should I do I just talk to agent Wagner or somebody I think that agent Wagner would be the appropriate
contact
to
proceed with an amended application.
>> Okay
any way we can have a copy of the paperwork from
the engineer? The
>> letter from
engineer Hanfield the advisory
is posted on the
Andover
Town website
and
if you have a copy of the agenda of the meeting
there is a link
to the
okay
yeah
I can look it up online and again
>> those
comments and the comments in
the discussion tonight,
which will be included in the minutes for this meeting,
I think will give you a roadmap
to move forward.
>> Okay. Okay.
All right. So, I think that should be it because he talked, he said, agent Wagner said what I was gonna say about the septic because the septic was already approved.
>> Right.
We would need that
on record for this application and we would need the indication
that the approved
upgrades will be sufficient
for the additional construction that you're now
asking for,
okay?
Do you have anything else
no
okay thank you so much so we'll keep working
>> on it okay well we'll look forward to receiving that amended application then
all right thank you Okay.
>> So,
I guess we have,
no further
discussion on that application
and I will move forward
to item seven on the agenda enforcement
actions.
We have
two linked enforcement
actions,
the
activities at 33 And 41 Route 87.
I
haven't seen anything new
online
and
I'll ask
Agent Wagner
if he is aware of any new activity or any new communications
regarding
those
enforcement actions.
>> Actually
I visited both properties.
I met with Kurt and Sandra.
I was able to get
the insurance information
for Mark Williams, the the contractor that's gonna be doing the remediation
for Kurt. Uh-huh. So they now have
Sandra Nichols now has
granted permission
for
Kurt's contractor, Mark Williams, to access
41 Route 87,
which is the Nichols property
to remove
that material.
And
last time I talked to Kurt,
Mark Williams was out of state for a month or so. So I'm waiting to hear from Kurt when as to when Mark will be back and ready to
start working on that job.
Right now he has permission to access the Nichols property.
Mark Williams does.
>> Okay, so that
at least represents
a tiny increment of progress
for the situation at forty one.
However,
I take it that
act that the
shed
at
Number 33 is still there
and the fill is still there.
And were you able to visit the site and
view any further activities that were alluded to
in the,
communication
from Nichols' attorney?
>> Yeah. I didn't see
anything anything further from my first visit.
So
I was just going off the
what
was there for before was yeah, it was pretty much to what was there when I went again. So the shed was there, there wasn't any significant erosion.
I didn't notice any fresh cut trees,
anything like that.
So
when I talked to Kurt, we were trying to put priority on
getting 41 Route 87 cleaned up so that
the other neighbor wasn't in, know,
getting our property cleaned up and then we work on
putting a permit in to
relocate the shed and then having to remediate that.
>> Okay and I understand again from your previous
comments,
we should be getting an application
for a
shed
that's smaller
than the existing shed
and located
elsewhere
but still in the Upland review area?
>> Yeah. We're looking at other we're actually looking at keeping the same shed because he said his opportunity to get the smaller one
came and went.
But but I think we could work something in with the new with the with the larger shed in a different area. Move it somewhere.
So
>> that's the whole. Okay, so this is a great leap somewhere,
so to speak. Frankly,
it
has been a
frustrating
and
drawn out process,
well with one thing and another
and I realized that you know you came into this
as
the
what the not not exactly the pinch hitter but the designated new hitter
for trying to get this enforcement action taken care of. But the fact is
it's still
a situation
that where we have a shed that was you know we
don't have an approved application,
we have a shed that's in violation,
and we have
wetlands activity
in violation.
We have
the
order to remediate,
from
February
and we had the
show cause hearing on March 2
and
basically
nothing
has
happened
and
I
don't know
if we need to
go to our next step
in order to make anything happen.
>> Well I I think
from what I mean, like you said, I'm coming into it partway through.
Talking to Kurt, he was under the impression that he wasn't supposed to do anything until he got that letter.
So what I was going to do is
now that he got the letter, I think that was last week.
>> You mean you're by letter, you were referring to The permission to access the Nichols property. Yeah, well, that's 41.
I'm talking about 33,
which he hasn't done anything about.
And if he was under the impression that he should wait for permission
to work at forty one, to work at 33.
I don't think that follows and I think he was under the wrong impression
because
know any you know he could have submitted
an amended application,
he
could have
undertaken work on his own property to remediate the situation
on that side of the creek,
and
essentially
it keeps getting deferred.
So
I would say at this point, at the very least, you should communicate to him that
he damn well better get
some action
on his side of the crick
and soon
because
the commission can't wait forever.
And
the next step would be
communicating with Attorney Brantz
and requesting
his
action
with
perhaps
requesting an injunction and fines
in Superior Court.
So if you could communicate that to
Mr. Baum in no uncertain terms,
I think that we could
defer
to our next meeting.
All right, will do.
Okay, any other comments from other commissioners? Mr. Smith?
>> Yeah,
I'd like to see a firm deadline
with that letter if possible.
Like by our next meeting,
progress must be made
or even the project completed,
which might be a little bit extreme. But I remember our first visit there,
I remember we made it pretty clear the things that needed to be done.
So
we've had this up on the agenda for so many times now. It just seems like we just keep on
letting it ride. But not saying we let it ride, but it's time to get it
done and over with.
>> Yeah, I would say that at the very least
we absolutely would have to have a permit application
with respect to the shed.
And
we would also have to see some evidence
that
work is proceeding at forty one at the very least and also at thirty three. We understand that
work at thirty three
is going to be contingent on moving the shed,
and so the shed has got to be moved.
Now as to its permanent location,
that's going to require a permit.
>> But he has to remove a boulders lot and everything else right that's been dumped down there.
Yes,
>> he's got to get at that, he can't just let it sit. Right, that's what I saying he's got to get the shed out of the way before he can get out the fill
that was
unlawfully deposited
in the watercourse,
and
that means the shed, you know, as I say, the ultimate location of the shed will require a permit.
We denied a permit,
the permit request to move it what eight feet,
so
you know there's got to be an acceptable location for the shed
but in the meantime but
that's assuming the shed stays on the property frankly I don't care if it's in his front yard
but it's got to move.
Okay Commissioner Larson, do you want to weigh in on this?
>> Oh I agree with everything you said George. It's time and Ed it's time
for that shed to
get out of there especially you know one of these days it's gonna start raining again and
We don't, we hope.
>> We
need to get the situation
resolved before we get to rainy season.
>> Okay.
So, Agent Wagner to communicate,
in no uncertain terms
that,
action is required here.
Okay. Okay.
Think you got the gist of it, right?
Okay
all right
so
moving on
well we can segue right into the agent report
>> Alright. So
one thing on here, investigation
of citizen complaint,
wetland disturbance
on private property at 139 Hebron Road.
And
I think that's the the wood piles and stuff that think it was Jed mentioned earlier that we saw during the sidewalk.
Maria Thulman wrote the letter. She didn't
put any contact information on her letter. So I was just able to get her phone number tonight. So I'm gonna give her a call, but I couldn't give her a call or
write her back because there's no contact info.
It appears that the letter describes all the previous disturbances
that
obviously we saw during the sidewalk. So I don't think it's anything any new activity.
But I'll contact
Mrs. Tollman now that I have her phone number and
make sure I'll confirm that that's
in fact the case.
>> If I may ask, it seems that the
boundaries
were unclear and is
Ms. Holman asserting that the activity spilled over
onto her property.
Yeah. Okay.
>> Yeah, I think that woodpile I remember seeing that you could there was some blue stakes that marked the property boundary and the woodpile extended over it.
I'm gonna probably
set up a visit or or at least talk to her on the phone and and she can explain
exactly what what the complaint is.
Okay.
Very good.
So moving on.
>> The
review of standard permit conditions.
I
had sent an
email to Megan. I sent one to you too. I don't know if you could post it
on I
>> hadn't received that as of the start
of the meeting.
Yeah. No,
I would not be able Unless
Mindy has it.
>> I don't think she has it because I just emailed Megan
and hopes that she could share it.
Well, go ahead. I'll check my email while you
>> Yeah.
Basically, he
recommended
three or four changes to our standard permit conditions.
So I wrote a
I included them in red
and a copy and then he put some feedback in there. So I included them on notes.
So basically we would need a public hearing to amend those because it's a part of the regulations.
The We don't amend our regulations anyhow,
so Yeah.
But that could be included in the amendment.
>> Okay, I found those emails. I'm going to see if I can forward them
to Jed and Ed at least
while we're working here.
Okay, forwarded two emails
to Jed and Ed and we'll see how many trips around the world they have to take
to show up in their inboxes.
But at least we've got the summary now. And as you said, would have to take official action
and have a hearing and all that.
So
maybe we can forego further discussion at this point. But at least we have that information in hand.
And as
you say, you noted the
exceptions there,
the salient details of what we might need to
address
in our regulations.
Yeah.
>> And the
last thing I had was
a review of
area towns
procedures for public works projects,
which I thought I I
briefed last month.
I think
the chair wanted examples of the minimum impact permit that other towns used for agent approval.
Yeah. So anything that that goes through the agent, they would have a like a reduced fee, a smaller permit, you know, like a one or two page permit.
So I I emailed them to George.
Yeah. And I forwarded those. Yeah. So there's three separate well, there's one from Coventry. I picked a small town, like a medium sized town in a city, and they're they're a little bit different, but
we could take a look at those two and
maybe think about incorporating a minimum impact permit
into our regulations when we decide to revise them.
Okay. So that would make projects
in the Upperland upland review or or other
minimum impact. Well, basically anything in the Upland review
could possibly fall into that.
>> Okay, and again, as we said,
this would be particularly relevant for our
town
activities
so that the
road crew
doesn't necessarily have to go through a full application
process to
fix a drain line or something like that.
Okay, well,
thanks for pulling that information together.
And
of course, commissioners will have to review that. And again since there will be
amendments to the application
we should probably address that in connection with the upgrades to our
amendments to our regulations
required by
changes in state statutes.
We're
gonna have
even more on our plate,
but we're still gonna have to address it soon enough.
Yeah.
Okay.
Let's see. Getting back to the agenda,
which is now buried under several layers of It's as good as anybody yet.
Okay.
So
agent report covered and
other business.
Okay, resignations and appointments.
As I indicated earlier at the beginning of the meeting,
Ms. Anderson has a declined appointment.
And as far as I know, the
appointment of
William Monroe is still pending. I don't have any information on
other applications
for open alternate positions.
Is anyone else aware of any
activity in that regard?
Okay.
9B something about
Planning and Zoning Lake District Special Regulations presentation
and I see that Linda Derek
is on the call
and of course Jed as P and Z
would also probably be aware of this so could
you all enlighten
me
and others
about this
presentation?
>> George, I'm
giving the presentation.
In
planning and zoning, we've been working on
lake rigs for probably close to two years at this point. And
we had some significant turnover both as chairman of the planning zoning commission and
the zoning agent
disrupted the progress
on that for a little bit.
But
I think we're up and running, moving
forward on that.
At the last,
Alma, Andover Lake Management Association,
and Alcoa,
Andover Lake Property Owners Association,
I was asked when
I reported that the lake regs weren't complete,
I was asked that at the October meeting
maybe I could give a little update
on those.
And I wasn't sure,
well I do know that
those regulations will impact the Inland Wetlands Commission. And in fact,
when we were talking about
putting the shed at 151
Lakeside Drive,
these regulations
would
be very helpful
in
regulatory
with respect to
mitigation
measures that we would take
to
mitigate the runoff because we've increased the impervious service
by 400 square feet by putting a shed.
So I do have a little presentation that I was going to go through that
Alma ALPOA meeting
next Wednesday, not
this one coming up, but on the fourteenth.
And I thought I would show that to the wetlands committee tonight. And there's a couple of people from
PAMA board
tuned in to take a look at it so they're not surprised by what it is that I put out to
the public when we have our next I was
going to get together with the Alma board
this Wednesday and give them a private viewing, but the freedom of information regulations
kind
of suggest that everything
we do needs to be done in the public domain. And so this
meeting gave me the opportunity to do that. Okay.
So the next
trick will be in I think I'll try to share my screen here and I need Mindy to
make me a cohost so that I can
make the presentation.
I just sent the request.
Okay.
You're live.
>> Yeah,
here we go.
One question that came up when we had the last meeting was where is the Andover Lake District and where is the watershed? And so I can at least address
those.
So here we go.
We're trying to improve the water quality in Andover Lake.
And there's a couple of different reasons for doing this.
You know the town is interested
in this because
if the water quality of the lake
continues to degrade even though it's degrading ever so slightly,
you know at some point the
Department of Energy and Environmental Protection may come in and say, Andover, you need to put sewers in,
which is very costly
and not a lot of excitement about doing that right now.
The good news for those of us who live around the lake is that
with the town being enthused about us improving the water quality,
we in the vicinity of the lake directly benefit from that and so that's certainly of interest
to all of us.
The lake regs that we're working on,
and
I'm
not going to show you all the verbiage that goes along with it. What I'm trying to do is get the concept across
to people so that when we make the verbiage
match the concept, we've got regulations that work.
Are modeled after those that are in existence,
have been in existence for the past fifteen years or so in the town of Columbia.
And John Bellini who works with the town of Columbia as well
said that
Columbia Lake was showing
algae blooms and that sort of thing and
after they implemented this one,
the lake got better, got cleaner, they don't have algae bloom problems anymore
and they did have a lot of support from the people that lived around the lake to go implement the regulations and so that would be nice too.
Briefly, how do the contaminants get into the lake? Well as the rain comes down through atmosphere it picks up contamination and it
gets ground
storm water runoff going into the lake. So that's
a big portion
of the nitrogen and phosphorus that goes into the lake.
And then we've also
got some septic systems
that due to the small lots
immediately surrounding the lake,
you are not in ideal systems
there. So we'll talk a little bit about septic systems going on too.
But the lake regulations would divide the Lake District and watershed into four zones.
And so
we start with zone A right around the lake, moving out from there, zone B, zone C and zone D as you get further away.
And we'll put more strict measures in place the closer we are to the lake.
So this shows that down at Andover
in
blue
down here, this is the Lake District
around Andover Lake.
And then this is the
overlay zone map
that we
generated
to work with
in conjunction with the regulations. And outlining in red
is
the outline of the watershed area and you can see an awful lot of our watershed resides in Columbia and Hebron.
And then again going back,
the blue line is the Lake District itself.
And so if you look at the yellow right around the lake,
that's what we refer to as Zone A.
That's where we're going to try to make the most significant reduction in the runoff into the lake.
And just the big picture, if somebody is going to go and make a significant improvement on their lot
and they're in Zone A,
we would like the end result to be that the water going into the lake
has 10% less phosphorus and nitrogen in it than it did before the guy starts whatever addition he's gonna put on. So he's going to have to take measures that mitigate
the water runoff so that the water going into the lake is cleaner than it used to be.
And that's sometimes not an easy task.
Zone B would be a reduction of 7.5%.
Zone C,
which is the purple,
that would be a reduction of
5%.
And then Zone D, which is the brown,
which is outside Lake District, it's still in the watershed,
we would have
no significant,
we wouldn't have to use what we're going to see as a nitrogen allocation
worksheet,
but they would have to mitigate
runoff from the increased impervious area
that they have.
So that's the map.
Again, if you
improve your property, one of the improvements should be improve the runoff into the lake. And as we talked about,
the nutrient allocation worksheet,
the reductions we just talked about there.
Additionally,
you must infiltrate the first two inch flush of storm water for volume of rain event from the newly increased surface area.
So in the case of 151
Lakeside Drive,
putting a shed into place of 400 square feet,
we would expect both a 10% reduction in runoff
and then the ability to infiltrate
the two inches
of storm water running down off that impervious surface to go something to do something to mitigate that from
running into the lake. And normally that would be a trench filled with stones or something like that so
that it doesn't all just run off into the lake there.
If you were doing a minor improvement
and in Zone A it's 100 square feet, B is 200, C is 300,
and then again in Zone D, you don't need to use the worksheet.
Wouldn't require the use of the worksheet, but still requires mitigation of the two inch rainfall runoff.
So that's what we're looking to do to
capture
the stormwater runoff into the lake.
This is
the first page of that nutrient allocation worksheet
and
as you can see it still
refers to Columbia Lake Watershed at the top of the page there as opposed to Andover because you know we're just working
on making sure that we understand this worksheet before we go
make that part of our regulation.
The other thing that's interesting to note here is this block here
which has
the factors associated
with
the different
surfaces.
So if we look down here, woodland,
which is the original condition of land before anything's built on it or the mulch beds,
that's got a coefficient of 0.1
and it goes up to, you know, if we pave the driveway,
1.5.
So somebody who is
looking to build onto their house or put up a shed or anything like that,
we get all these numbers here
and we
put the number of square feet associated with each of these items in.
We'd multiply those times
this
factor for the runoff coefficient
and that gives you a number here. You add all this up and that's gonna give you the total
phosphorus
nitrogen runoff going into the lake.
And that's before you start to do any remodeling.
We would expect a 10% reduction of that and so that gives us the target that we're going to shoot for. So that's what this page does, that calculates
what's going on originally so we know how much better we want to make the water.
Here's the second page of that
and it's going to talk about, okay, if we're going to make the
water better,
what are we going to do? And it's got,
you know, we're going to change lawn to mulch bed and that shows an improvement
there.
And you've got all these different things,
challenges to go through and show what are we doing to
improve it.
And then you get a load reduction when you tally all that up.
And that's got to come and take you down to below that 10% improvement we were looking at.
So there's still a couple of bugs that we're trying to work on as
we
figure out how to use this worksheet.
But the worksheet is really the nuts and bolts of what we would be doing.
If you're in zone B, it's a seven and a half percent reduction instead of zone A.
Okay, so when when would you be required to use this nutrient allocation worksheet according to our regulations?
If you're building a new house on a lot, you gotta use the worksheet.
If you're improving more than 50% of the structure square footage within a ten year period, what we're trying to do there is make sure that we don't incrementally
improve
the structure on the lake so that we can avoid improving the water quality going into the lake. We want to make sure that
if you're improving your lot, you're improving the water quality.
Increasing the floor area
and that
varies by zone, most strictly in Zone A,
the least restrictive in Zone C.
If you add the accessory structure
like
a shed,
again it varies by zone
in
increasing the impervious surface area, putting in a bigger driveway, paving a driveway, all those things, we get you there.
So these are the things that would require use of that worksheet.
As we said earlier on, if it was less than 100 square feet we were adding, then you wouldn't have to use the worksheet, you just have to
accommodate the runoff from that particular
surface.
Moving on to septics, you know the Lake District, a lot of small lots
with
the
small lots having wells and septic systems.
The majority of the septic systems
are pretty old at this point.
A lot of them are undersized
not meeting the minimum separation distance to groundwater or to the lake.
And
the existing septic systems are often located in the water table for at least a good portion of the year.
These regulations would apply to Zone A and Zone B, the two zones that are closest
to the lake.
So the conditions required a new septic
in those if you're increasing
the use requiring
a B100 approval under the Connecticut Public Health Code that requires a new septic septic system.
Net floor area of the principal building increases by 20 or 30%
for Zone A, Zone B,
the new septic.
Increasing the overall footprint of the principal structure
by 25 or 30%
for all the structures combined if you were adding a shed, an accessory apartment, anything like that to 40
or 50%,
again we'd be looking at
the new septic system in there.
Anytime we're adding one or more bedrooms
and when greater than 50% of the principal structure square footage is rebuilt
and there's any increase in living area requiring a B100 approval.
I
did get a
email back from Art who couldn't join us tonight. He was asking me about this particular thing
and I thought he had a good comment there.
His comment was if you're tearing down a
house and rebuilding it but you're not making it
any bigger, don't we care about the septic system?
And we do.
So I've got to take a look at the wording on that one, but that would be our intention. You don't necessarily have to make it bigger.
If you're going to rebuild your house,
it might be a good time to redo your septic tank as well.
And regulation is cumulative as of the date of the regulation.
So again, if you do a little bit here, a little bit there, then you add up to meet these requirements,
that's when we go in to take a look at the condition of your septic system.
Somebody could say, well I just put in a new septic system a year or two ago.
And so there are some exemptions. If you met one of those requirements to
ensure that you have a good septic system,
if you get an engineer in there and prove the existing system is greater than 12 inches above the max high water table,
that might be a factor that would say yeah you're good to go.
You're greater than 35 feet to the high water mark of the Andover Lake or tributary, the various streams that run into it,
that
might be okay.
And the last one,
I'm still a little fuzzy on
what this means myself and so I got to do some more homework on that, exceeds 50% of the size requirements for a new principal
building.
To me it seems like it should be,
we would want it to meet 100% of the new requirement,
but I am told all that's not true, I just haven't had anybody explain to me why fifty percent's
good enough on that yet.
So anyhow, we're trying to put the finishing touches on the worksheet
and so Jim and I, who are both new to our positions,
is Jim the zoning agent and me as the chairman of planning and zoning.
We understand the regulations and can explain them to those who might be asking us questions about those.
There are still a couple of new construction lots around the lake and
obviously if you have a
wooded lot
and you want to build on it, there's no way you can make the well.
There are, I guess, probably a couple of ways you can make it better than a forested lot by putting in dry wells and that sort of thing. But it's very difficult to
improve that. So we've got to come up with some method for giving somebody a basic allowance
for what we expect when you are building new construction on a lot
and how we make allowances for that so that it's actually doable.
One of the concerns I had were the mechanisms in place to trigger use of the worksheet as I walk around the lake. You know, I see lots of new paved driveways going in and that sort of thing. I'm not sure how
that
gets triggered down at town hall so that
we can actually go out to the property owner and say, you know, we need to mitigate all those things. So it's going to take coordination with the Inland Wetlands Commission, planning zoning, zoning
board of appeals,
and that sort of thing to make sure that we get this over to zoning so that we can put the mitigation measures in place.
And then there's still some minor corrections to the regulations that we've been working on and I think Linda you had a copy of that.
There's
some points we need to smooth out, one of which is the issue that Art brought up on
the teardown house and how that gets factored in.
So that's really
the concept of what we're looking at. I know that went through it
very quickly
but that's
what I was going to show
on Wednesday the fourteenth at the meeting and
while we probably don't have a lot of time to go
through a lot of questions and discussions on it tonight,
I'd be happy to entertain any questions or discussion on it when we get to the Alma Alpoa meeting on the fourteenth and spend as much time
as you guys want there. And this gives you a chance to
think about a little bit and ask questions then. Don't know that I'll have all the answers but
now's a good time to get the questions so that we can build the answers into it as we continue working on these.
And I think that's
all that we've got before these get put into effect they would have to go to public hearing
and
certainly having strong support from
Alma and Alcoa
would be very helpful at that public hearing.
>> Well, thanks, Joe, for sharing that preview.
It's good to see further
action after all the discussion we had
with John Valenti when he was serving as wetlands agent for the town.
And going through the worksheet and the need to reduce
nutrient inputs
the lake to maintain its quality.
And I
hope that you'll get further input
and be able to resolve some of the glitches especially
I noticed Ed was
throwing out some comments in the chat line about the
you know the nature of different
kinds of education and so forth so getting that worksheet straight
I think will be a key to successful implementation
and then of course our part in terms of any regulatory actions and regulatory revisions that need to be made,
I'm sure we'll be willing to take those up
when the time comes.
>> And I was hoping to have gone through the worksheet. Here's the example on 151 Lakeside Drive
with John last Wednesday we were planning to meet to go over that and
there was a little storm blew through. We didn't get too much of it but he had a couple of trees down around his house and he had no power
and so he was going off to deal with that and I didn't get to meet with him to go through
the questions that I had on working
the worksheet. What would
>> we do with that 400 square feet of impervious surface
and where is he going to put the rain garden
>> to? Well,
so I did ask John that and his answer was
that
he thought the best way to go about that was to
dig down underneath where the
shed was going to go and fill it up with the crushed stone more so that it's got a
detention basin, if you will, for that water to sit in and
perk down in through the ground
and that sort of thing.
And I thought that sounded good but then it brings up a whole new can of issues with the Wetlands Commission because
thought it was a big deal that he wasn't going to excavate to put in the shed. Now we're talking about telling them to excavate. So it's
going to be
a little bit of a mixed bag but I think we do need to do something to start making the water in the lake
be improved a little bit year over year so that we're in good shape there.
And hopefully we'll get the support of the surrounding residents
to do that because
they are gonna have to
foot the bill for it, as you say.
And when you're doing the shed,
bill for the mitigation measures could be a good portion of the total bill for that project
as it comes out.
Could indeed.
>> George, I don't know if you have any time to just get any immediate feedback from the folks who sat in or not or
yeah I
>> guess we have time for a couple of questions or comments but I'll first ask if Commissioner Smith has anything
you'd like to say at this point I say I was following your comments
in the chat line but anything you want to
convey
I'm just asking a bunch of questions
Okay.
>> This is finally in my ballpark a little bit. What you guys do is above and beyond my can.
But the environmental stuff is having been under Wyndham Water Commission,
I drove the commission to conduct the largest watershed study in the state of Connecticut.
And we had Yukon, the ERI program come in and we identified,
we basically went out and all those input streams and everything throughout the watershed at the Nabasitok
Watershed.
And we located some inputs that we never knew about that were really high in excess of nutrients and things. So I'm just curious about the streams coming in,
as a rain event develops.
Have we ever sent
a team out to just get some
of the input
coming in to see what the load is
for nutrients and things?
>> There's a you wanna speak to that? Yeah, sure. Hi, Ed. I work as a consultant for the Lake Andover property owners.
And we've done a lot of stormwater sampling and consistent base flow monitoring there. So we do have a pretty good long term data set.
>> Okay, great.
And do we ever did we ever consider having a single septic service kind of contract with everybody around the lake and then No, come
>> I don't think so. But that would be a good idea because there would be better transparency about the type of inspections that they're doing.
>> Then we'd have a relationship with them. One truck
load can handle multiple houses.
Could do it during their off season.
It would become part of a regular
service and
we'd get reports back like,
we noticed the septic is starting to fail
versus now we might not ever hear about those sorts of things. Right.
>> We were approached by one company
a couple of years ago
offering
you know for the larger number of families that participated
everybody would get a lower
fee
We could
return to that and consider it.
>> I think that speaks to less so with the regulations and more so of overall planning planning within within the the watershed, watershed though. Though.
Jed, I had made some comments on the draft that I was sent, so if we could maybe get together and talk about it at some point, that would be it. If you're willing to entertain some additional technical questions, I'd really appreciate it. Okay, yeah. And if you could, both you and Ed, if you could email me your questions so I can have a chance to take a look at them and not be stumped right off the bat when you
>> lay them on me. That gives me a chance to prepare a little bit too. That would be helpful.
And certainly as we go to the meeting on the October 14,
I'm expecting to get feedback
there as well and
maybe
we could go through there. I know
John Valenti, Jim and I are planning to get together next Wednesday at 11:00
over at the town hall. I don't know your availability there, Hillary,
but we are planning to go spend some time.
>> That's the fourteenth?
Yeah,
yeah. As
of now I'm not free on that day but we can talk and I'll see what I can do. Okay very good thanks for joining us Hilary. Yeah thanks for it was a good presentation thank you.
Linda?
>> Well I think
I think maybe Alma question is yeah how do we so
if you and Hillary and John if you're having this
meeting and maybe there's some adjustments to the language such as it is right now
So coming on the fourteenth might have
slight
adjustments.
And then what's the procedure
going forward before it goes to hearing?
Like how much
discussion do you entertain? How much wiggle room is there for revision
>> to a final project product? You would see if you looked at the planning and zoning
agendas,
there's going to have to be a couple of months where we spend some time during
our public meetings
working on the regulations, getting them in a final form where
we're ready to present them to the public before we you know, act on them and
we
want them to be as good as we can get them there and the public's always invited to those sessions
where we're working on
the,
we're making the sausage, so to speak. Hopefully
when the sausage is ready for prime time we'll go to public hearing and
present that. So
it's going to be a little while.
>> So think that we're kind of digressing into areas that are really proper for Alma, Alpoha,
and P and Z,
and getting away from the subject of the
Inland Wetlands and Water Courses Commission meeting at hand. So I'll ask you to
carry on those conversations
as a sidebar or,
you know, by some other means so that we can proceed with the agenda for tonight's meeting.
The
next item on the agenda is bylaws revision.
And I'm going to request that we defer that since Jim Hallisey could not be present for this meeting and he was the one who made some valuable suggestions about the IWWC
bylaws.
And I would want him to be present
for any discussion of revisions.
>> Can I just thank the people that did join us tonight to hear the presentation before they go And drifted
>> before we sign off, thank you Jed and thanks for letting us come and thanks Jed it was a great presentation,
very helpful? Okay,
nice. Okay, so long.
We'll be in touch. Bye.
>> Okay, so as I was saying,
final item on the other business is the online land use academy basic training. That's informational.
I
clicked on the links and basically
we have a couple of PowerPoint presentations,
some of it on legal aspects
and then remember we were supposed to have a workshop on
plan reading
that was cancelled because of COVID and that has now been translated
to an online presentation
and again we
are encouraged
to view those presentations
for our information
and to be better able to function
as board members or commissioners.
Has anybody checked those links besides me?
Nope. Okay,
well again I encourage you to do it and
again
some of it may be familiar we did have that workshop on that was conducted with PNC and other land use
agencies
some of the material seems to be from
that and then as I say the one on
plan reading
they've translated to an online format.
Item 10 our next regular meeting
will be Monday, November 2
at seven p. M. In the usual virtual time,
well the virtual place
from the Zoom server
and
with that
I am ready to entertain a motion for adjournment
I'll make a motion to adjourn I second okay
>> so Jed Larson
has
moved Edmund Smith has seconded,
moved to adjourn and we'll call for a vote. Jed
aye
>> aye George Eliot vote aye so the motion carries three zero zero the mode the meeting is adjourned
at 08:47
p. M.
Thank you all and I'm sorry I had to shake your chain to bring you here but I'm glad you were able to attend and make up a quorum so we can do our business.
Good night. Night everybody.
Well.
Mindy do you have any questions
before we ring off?
I don't I think I got everything down and then I'm just gonna relook You've over to glorious voices on tape too don't you? Yeah yeah and our expressions as well no face stars to cover up what we're saying.
Okay well thanks so much and see you next meeting.
Thank
you.